# **Thor Lindberg**

# Revkjavík, Iceland

**Email** thor@lindberg.is

Website lindberg.is

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/thorlindberg

## **Profile**

M.Sc. Design with an interdisciplinary background in the intersection between medical science and information technology. I leverage this by acting as a bridge between teams on a project, as I am versed in everything from organizational analysis to design specification to development and implementation. This is evident in my experience as an IT Consultant where I lead projects from initial analysis to feature specification to implementing final features in code.

I invest my spare time in supplementing my education through professional courses, building software, exploring Iceland, and traveling throughout the United States to network with others in tech.

## **Education**

IT University of Copenhagen 08/2020 - 06/2022

## Master of Science in Digital Design

Thesis: Type-Extensible Objection Notation (TXON)

• Explorative design for typedJSON objects.

# Relevant courses:

· React Native mobile development with Expo. Advanced Design Processes. UX Design.

Copenhagen University

08/2017 - 07/2020

## **Bachelor of Science in Health Informatics**

Thesis: Tools for caretakers of stroke victims

· Qualitative analysis to determine low-cost digital solutions for caretakers of stroke victims.

## Relevant courses:

· Statistics. Mathematical Modelling. Programming for Biosciences. IT Security. Medical Image Analysis. Interaction Design.

## **Skills**

**Projects** 

Language English (fluent), Icelandic (beginner) Components/variants, flows, auto layout **Figma Software** JSX, TypeScript, Swift, SwiftUI, Git **Analysis** Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib Data Excel, Visual Basic for Applications SharePoint, Azure, Office

# **Experience**

Netcompany

August 2022 - December 2023

#### IT Consultant

- · Lead the analysis and initial design phase of multiple client projects and authored feature and design documents.
- · Responsible for client contact, mediating meetings, status reporting, and managing the project timeline and tasks.
- · Provided clients with digital transformation strategies through analysis of business processes and IT infrastructure.
- · Contributed to source code for Java-based backend.
- · Contributed to code optimization and new features for a React Native and React Native for Web application.

National Special Crime Unit

October 2021 - July 2022

## **IT-Administrative Student**

- · Managed users of webportal and provided direct support.
- · Contributed to document processing architecture.
- · Authored documentation and website content.

IT University of Copenhagen

August 2021 — June 2022

## **Teaching Assistant**

- · Assisted with teaching UX Design specialization.
- · Assisted with assignments for courses in UX Design, Experimental Design, Python, and Javascript with MQTT.

Domino's Pizza

August 2021 — January 2022

#### Shift Leader

- · Responsible for managing the store, closing the store, registering inventory, and matching store orders with use.
- · Delegated work to bakers and delivery drivers.
- · Primary pizza baker during rush hours.

## Certificates

Mímir-simentun March 2024 - Now

## Introduction to Icelandic (written and spoken)

University of California, San Diego

March 2024 - Now

## **Data Structures and Algorithms Specialization**

Courses: Test-driven algorithm design. Dynamic programming. Advanced algorithms and data structures. Pattern matching.

Meta

March 2024 - Now

## Front-End Developer Professional Certificate

Courses: JavaScript. Version control. HTML and CSS. Advanced React with components, hooks, APIs, and testing. UX/UI design.

## **Published**

Áfangastaður - Explore Iceland

apps.apple.com/app/id6466740299

iPhone application for exploring locations in Iceland, written in React Native and leveraging frameworks such as Redux Toolkit and React Context.